Let's say, you want to order results by account,
لنقل، إنكم تريدون ترتيب النتائج حسب الحساب،
and within each account,
وداخل كل حساب،
have orders sorted from largest to smallest,
اطلبوا فرز الترتيبات من الأكبر إلى الأصغر،
so you'll be able to quickly see what the largest orders were for each account.
بحيث تتمكنون من رؤية الترتيبات الأكبر في كل حساب بسرعة.
You can use an ORDER BY over multiple columns to achieve this,
يمكنكم استخدام الترتيب حسب في أعمدة متعددة لتحقيق هذا،
and the sorting will happen in the order that you specify the columns.
وسيحدث الفرز بالترتيب الذي تُحدِدون الأعمدة به.
So, let's start by ordering by the account_id, and then, total_amt_usd,
إذًا، لنبدأ في الترتيب حسب account_id، وبعد ذلك، total_amt_usd،
which we'll make DESCENDING,
الذي سنجعله تنازليًّا،
so the largest values will be first.
لذا ستكون القيم الأكبر أولاً.
So I run this, you can see that the first account we get is 1001,
لقد شغّلت هذا، ويمكنكم معرفة أن الحساب الأول الذي وصلنا إليه هو 1001،
and then the orders descend from 9426 all the way down.
ومن ثمّ يتم عد الترتيبات تنازليًّا من 9426 حتى الأسفل.
And then after that, we have 1021 and that account's largest orders and so forth.
بعد ذلك، نصل إلى 1021 والترتيبات الأكبر في هذا الحساب وهكذا.
Now what happens, if I flip this,
الآن، ماذا يحدث، إذا قمتُ بعكس هذا،
so the amount will be first, and then we sort by account.
فإن المبلغ سيكون أولاً، وسنكون قد قمنا بالفرز حسب الحساب.
What's happening here is that we're starting with
يتلخص الأمر الذي يحدث هنا في أننا نبدأ بالمبلغ الأكبر
the highest amount and sorting descending.
ونقوم بالفرز تنازليًّا.
So, this is the largest order of all time at $232207 and that went to account 4251.
إذًا، هذا هو أكبر ترتيب على الإطلاق وهو 232207 دولارات وهو انتقل إلى حساب 4251.
Now, It doesn't seem to be sorting by account id.
الآن، لا يبدو أن الفرز تم حسب معرّف الحساب.
The reason for that is that,
والسبب في ذلك هو أن
all of these amounts are so precise that there aren't multiple rows of the same amount.
جميع هذه المبالغ دقيقة جدًا بحيث لا توجد صفوف متعددة للمبلغ نفسه.
So, if there were two rows in the set with the exact same amount,
في حالة وجود صفين في المجموعة بهما المبلغ نفسه بالضبط،
you might notice that account ID within that is sorted from smallest to largest.
قد تلاحظون أن معرّف الحساب داخل هذا يتم فرزه من الأصغر إلى الأكبر.
But, since we're just sorting by the total amount column,
لكن، نظرًا لأننا نقوم بالفرز فقط حسب عمود إجمالي المبلغ،
then we don't see that here.
فإننا عندئذٍ لا نرى هذا هنا.